Have you ever joined a cloud environment where someone accidentally
turned on a risky feature like enabling the external IPs on a
sensitive VM and nobody noticed until it was too late? That's where
Google Cloud organization policy can help.
Let's just go to the Google Cloud console.
I'm inside the Google Cloud console.
On the top, I have selected the organization.
That's important.
These policies apply downward from where you set them.
Now let's go to the IAM and go to the Organization policies for your entire
cloud environment. If IAM can answer who can do what,
then organization policy answer what is allowed to happen. And
the magic is once a policy is enforced here,
every folder, every project,
and every resource inherits it unless explicitly overridden.
Serial port access is useful for debugging,
but in the production it can expose sensitive information.
So to avoid that, let's disable that. In the filter, let me search constraint,
and constraint is compute.disableSerialPortAccess.
Now right now you can see that it is Inactive.
I can click on these three dots and say Edit policy,
and I switch it from inheritance to override parent's policy and say Add a rule,
and I'm saying that Enforcement is On and say Set policy.
Now, no VM in the organization,
current or future, can enable serial port access unless a
folder or a project explicitly overrides it.
This is one of the first policies many security teams enforce
because it prevents accidental exposure of logs,
commands, RVM internals.
That's how you can keep on adding more and more enforcements.
For example, from here you can put an enforcement to the location constraint,
to the constraint for external IP creation,
service account creation, and many more.
So this will automatically drill down to the projects and the applications.